<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">Martinho Aragão</title>
<generator uri="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="" />
<updated>2015-08-28T21:10:39+01:00</updated>
<id>/</id>
<author>
  <name>Martinho Aragão</name>
  <uri>/</uri>
  <email>martinhoaragao+website@gmail.com</email>
</author>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Making a template my own]]></title>
  <link>/refactor-blog</link>
  <id>/refactor-blog</id>
  <updated>2015-08-28T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2015-08-28T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Martinho Aragão</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>martinhoaragao+website@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As I was structuring my website, I came upon many Jekyll templates, some of which I forked.
One of them, was &lt;a href=&quot;http://willkoehler.net&quot;&gt;Will Koehler’s&lt;/a&gt; a simplistic, intuitive but most importantly neatly coded.
In fact, he refactored one of the blogs in Jekyll’s list, and wrote a &lt;a href=&quot;http://willkoehler.net/2014/08/26/save-50-hours-setting-up-your-jekyll-blog.html&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; about what he did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, in the same fashion, I took the long approach and this post is about what I have done to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/hmfaysal/hmfaysal-omega-theme&quot;&gt;HMFAYSAL omega theme&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To begin with, I chose to personalise my blog, for the opportunity to get to know Jekyll and by extension Ruby and Javascript.
For that reason, even if I had found the perfect theme I would still most likely want to edit a few things just to learn and make it my own.
As it is, it is also functions as my sandbox to try out new things.
Though, this last argument is only fully achieved as I do not intend to mass advertise this website at least as of now, instead I have other goals, as I have explained over &lt;a href=&quot;/hello-world&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back to HMFAYSAL’s theme, I was impressed when I saw its design, clearly one that I would never be able to achieve on my own.
Well, it’s true that I lack talent in that area, but that would be another story.
Yet what I noticed was that despite how phenomenal the theme was, the code that built it was messier than what I was used to.
This can be easily explained by its author background, which you may read more about in the link I provided above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, in no particular order here is what I did thus far:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;update&quot;&gt;Update&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Font Awesome&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bootstrap&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Changed a few classes in order to keep the same style.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;simplify-design&quot;&gt;Simplify design&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Navbar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Footer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Overall details&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reduced clutter, instead of clicking to access a menu, placed the buttons I needed on top, and removed the navbar on the footer.
Also decreased the size of the social buttons along with other small things such as changed fonts and their size.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;remove-categories&quot;&gt;Remove Categories&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Considering this is a tiny blog about what I do, I had no need for both tags and categories.
For that reason,and because tags are more versatil, more than one allowed per post, I removed categories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;fix&quot;&gt;Fix&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;404 Error page&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rake new posts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as I recall the links for the error page were outdated.
Regarding the Rake new posts, changed it to accept arguments in the command-line through spaces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;add&quot;&gt;Add&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rake deploy by command by Will Koehler and adjusted to master instead of gh-pages.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Search by tag, quit with esc or click outside&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SEO
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Minify&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Add robots.txt&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Code
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Organise into assets pipeline
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Change css to sass, and split by sections&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Javascript in separate files&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this is mostly the section where I learnt, changing to the assets pipeline required me to go through almost every single file, removing unneeded lines and adjusting some to my style.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;whats-next&quot;&gt;What’s next?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Focus on posting for a while, hopefully adjust quickly to that routine.
Afterwards get more feedback, and perhaps even review the code again to ensure nothing was left behind.&lt;/p&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/refactor-blog&quot;&gt;Making a template my own&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Martinho Aragão at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Martinho Aragão&lt;/a&gt; on August 28, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hello, world!]]></title>
  <link>/hello-world</link>
  <id>/hello-world</id>
  <published>2015-07-29T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2015-07-29T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Martinho Aragão</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>martinhoaragao+website@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yo!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my website, as you can see, and despite my initial doubts, it became a blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So through this post I mean to cover the reasoning behind this webpage, my goals, fears and what I have in mind for the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But first things first. Why did I start this?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although, I tried to do a plain single paged website about myself, I found that I was not able to capture what I was all about. This might sound quite peculiar, even more so knowing that I was never a fan of blogging, but I understood I had more to gain by embracing this as a challenge. So here go some of the reasons I keep talking about:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;English - A way to properly practice my English writing skills while also motivating me to read more;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Playground - Somewhere I could apply proper CSS and JS with no time constraints;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Organisation - Having to structure each post before writing is certainly a way to speed up how I organise what I do;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Counter procrastination - Since I am also affected by procrastination, having to write a post about every 2 week is a way to counter my own habits, else the internet will register I have failed;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Controlled share environment - A fancy way for saying I am not a fan of posting in Social Media as I don’t find them to be is not the most auspicious place to talk about serious stuff.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Truth be said, it has been already quite tough for me to do this post from start to end, as some people might attest, I’ve scrapped it too often, hopefully after a few times doing it should be less of an hassle. Anyway, I’ve already scheduled my next posts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Refactor Blog - What I did to change the template;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;YME - My last 2 years in Young Minho Enterprise;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nutrium - Startup Talk;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Brainstorming - How I prepare for a post.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now back to the code, so in a few weeks I can post about the Blog!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/hello-world&quot;&gt;Hello, world!&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Martinho Aragão at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Martinho Aragão&lt;/a&gt; on July 29, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Worse than ever]]></title>
  <link>/worse-than-ever</link>
  <id>/worse-than-ever</id>
  <published>2015-06-30T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2015-06-30T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Martinho Aragão</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>martinhoaragao+website@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Building on &lt;a href=&quot;http://willkoehler.net/2014/08/26/save-50-hours-setting-up-your-jekyll-blog.html&quot;&gt;Will Koehler’s post&lt;/a&gt;, I’ve taken the long way.
By that, I mean I chose to personalise my blog, after all it’s an opportunity to get to know not only Jekyll, but also SEO and Javascript, it is where I intend to test out new things.
So, after kinda like a robot myself, I settled on the amazing &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hossainmohdfaysal.com/hmfaysal-omega-theme/&quot;&gt;HMFAYSAL Omega Theme&lt;/a&gt; yet, despite the amazing design, which I could never reach by myself, the code seemed messier than my own. Though thanks to that, I get to refactor a project!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the progress so far:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Update to new version
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Font Awesome&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Bootstrap&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Simplify to Minimal style
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Navbar&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Footer&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove Categories&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fix 404 Error page&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add rake deploy by command&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add minify and robots.txt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improve search - by tag, quit with esc or mouse outside&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create about page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To Do:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finish splitting into assets pipeline
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Sass by sections&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;JS in separate files&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fix data Errors&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Evaluate minimal design changes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Check cross browser&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clean files&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do my first actual post!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Other stuff that I forgot&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fix rake new post&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/worse-than-ever&quot;&gt;Worse than ever&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Martinho Aragão at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Martinho Aragão&lt;/a&gt; on June 30, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hardly Working]]></title>
  <link>/hardly-working</link>
  <id>/hardly-working</id>
  <published>2015-06-22T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2015-06-22T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Martinho Aragão</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>martinhoaragao+website@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hardly Working&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of right now, I’m focusing on cleaning up the code to what I need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, I’m building up my first post. As soon as it is done, this shall be replaced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But don’t stop coming here just because of that! I shall be as swift as the wind, although I’m neither saying there is wind, nor that it is fast as of right now, you should check the weather forecast.
Oh, I’m so funny. . .&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/hardly-working&quot;&gt;Hardly Working&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Martinho Aragão at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Martinho Aragão&lt;/a&gt; on June 22, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>

</feed>
